Guide to the Philip G. Zimbardo Papers SC0750
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Philip G. Zimbardo papers
1953-2017
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Zimbardo, Philip G.
SC0750
256 Linear Feet 182 boxes
The materials consist of research and teaching files, professional files and correspondence, audiovisual materials, professional papers and articles, and materials documenting the Stanford Prison Experiment.
The materials consist of research and teaching files, professional files and correspondence, audiovisual materials used in the classroom, professional papers and articles, and materials documenting the Stanford Prison Experiment.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given by Philip G. Zimbardo to Stanford University, Special Collections in 2011-2012.
Information about Access
Some files in Series 6 (Stanford Prison Experiment) are restricted to protect participant privacy; consult the University Archivist for access.
Files in Series 9 (Restricted Materials) are restricted for 75 years from date of creation.
Otherwise the collection is open for research; audiovisual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy. Computer media series materials are in-process and currently unavailable.
Materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Philip Zimbardo was born on March 23, 1933 in New York City. He attended Brooklyn College where he earned a B.A. in 1954, triple majoring in psychology, sociology and anthropology. He then went on to earn his M.A. in 1955 and his Ph.D. in 1959 from Yale University, both in psychology.
He taught briefly at Yale before becoming a psychology professor at New York University, where he taught until 1967. After a year of teaching at Columbia University, he became a faculty member at Stanford University in 1968.
Philip Zimbardo is perhaps best known for the Stanford Prison Experiment, conducted in the basement of the Stanford University psychology department in 1971. The participants in the study were 24 male college students who were randomly assigned to act either as "guards" or "prisoners" in the mock prison.
The study was initially slated to last two weeks, but had to be terminated after just six days because of the extreme reactions and behaviors of the participants. The guards began displaying cruel and sadistic behavior toward the prisoners, while the prisoners became depressed and hopeless.
Since the famous prison experiment, Zimbardo has continued to conduct research on a variety of topics including shyness, cult behavior and heroism. He has a authored and co-authored numerous books, including some that are widely used in university level psychology courses. Some people may recognize him as the host of the Discovering Psychology video series, which has aired on PBS and is often used in high school and college psychology classes. In 2002, Zimbardo was elected president of the American Psychological Association. After more than 50 years of teaching, Zimbardo retired from Stanford in 2003 but gave his last "Exploring Human Nature" lecture on March 7, 2007.
Today, he continues to work as the director of the organization he founded called the Heroic Imagination Project. The organization promotes research, education and media initiatives designed to inspire ordinary people to act as heroes and agents of social change.
Description of the Collection
This collection documents the life of noted American psychologist Philip G. Zimbardo. The materials consist of Dr. Zimbardo's research and teaching files, professional files and correspondence, audiovisual materials used in the classroom, professional papers and articles, and materials documenting the Stanford Prison Experiment, for which he is perhaps best known.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged in nine series: Series 1. Audiovisual Materials; Series 2. Born-Digital Materials; Series 3. Professional Files; Series 4. Publications and Writing; Series 5. Research Files; Series 6. Stanford Prison Experiment; Series 7. Teaching Files; Series 8. Oversized Materials; Series 9. Restricted Materials.
Time perspective; Political psychology; Jonestown Mass Suicide, Jonestown, Guyana, 1978; College teachers.; Social Psychology; College teachers -- Political activity.; Terrorism; Prisoners of war -- Psychology; Psychology -- Study and teaching.; Prisons; Mental illness; Stanford University -- Faculty.; Psychology -- Experiments.; Hypnotism.; Cults; Cognitive dissonance; Burn out (Psychology); Brainwashing; Bashfulness; Bandura, Albert; Banks, W. Curtis; Jaffe, David; Haney, Craig; Stanford University. Department of Psychology; Layton, Deborah; Jones, Jim; Spain, Johnny; Layton, Laurence; Hearst, Patricia; Zimbardo, Philip G.; California State Prison at San Quentin; Zimbardo, Philip G.; Candid Camera, Inc.; Funt, Allen; Abu Ghraib Prison; Maslach, Christina; American Psychological Association.; Carducci, Bernardo J.; Fraser, Scott C. (Scott Cameron); Barbaranelli, Claudio; Caprara, Gian Vittorio
- Audiovisual materials, Series 1
  Scope and Contents
  Audiovisual materials consist primarily of videotapes, audiocassettes, and audio reels related to Zimbardo's primary research focuses. Topics include cults (particularly Jonestown/Peoples Temple), mind control, shyness, time perspective, evil, and the teaching of psychology.
  Note: there is some overlap between this series and the Stanford Prison Experiment series, where audiovisual materials related to the Stanford Prison Experiment also exists.
  Arrangement
  This series is divided into two subseries: videorecordings, and audiorecordings. Materials are arranged by subjects as originally assigned by Professor Zimbardo, and are described at the item level.
  - Videorecordings
    Videorecordings primarily consist of videotapes compiled for subject research from various television news programs such as Nightline, Dateline, 60 Minutes, 20/20, and 48 hours. Included are videotapes of Zimbardo's appearances on television programs, classroom lectures, and talks given at conferences and symposia. Also included are compilations of recorded television programs, and some films.
    There are two subseries within videorecordings: the first contains materials related to Zimbardo’s collaboration with Allen Funt for the video series Candid Camera Classics for Teaching Psychology, the second relates to research projects on the subject of discontinuity.
    - Mind Control-Prelude to war, Date Here if provided; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 22)
    - Brainwashing, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 22)
    - Circle of Power (Cult), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 22)
    - Holy Ghost Cult Snake Handlers, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 22)
    - News-Waco Cult/War Crimes Trial, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 22)
    - Waco Cult Massacre, 1993 Apr 19; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 22)
    - Koresh Cult-911 tape, 1993; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 22)
    - Dateline: "Cults", 1997 Apr 1; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 22)
    - Nightline: Satanic Cult Abuse/MPD, 1995 Oct 24; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 22)
    - 1. S Hassan-Harvard Talk: What went wrong with Waco?, 2. Post analysis of death and destruction of Koresh cult in Waco, TX, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 22)
    - Heaven's Gate Cult, 1999 Nov; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 22)
    - Cults: "Heaven's Gate, Part 2", 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 22)
    - Cults: True Behavior parts 1 & 2, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 22)
    - CAN, Aspects of mind control-by S. Hassan, Illustrated by 3 ex-cults (A. Wanda I.W.P., 4 1/2 yrs; B. Pat Brother Julius. 18yrs.; C. Monica-Scientology-Info control), 1994; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 22)
    - 60 Minutes: "Heaven's Gate, Parts 1 & 2" (03/30/97), 1997 Mar 30; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 22)
    - 48 Hours: "Deprogramming", 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 22)
    - Killer Cults: Episodes 1 & 2 of 3, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 22)
    - Dateline: Patty Hearst, mind control (03/21/1997), 1997 Mar 21; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 22)
    - 1. Martin Luther King, Jr. Speeches, 2. Jim Jones Speeches, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 22)
    - Moonchild, Prof. Zimbardo (60 Min.), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 22)
    - Cults-Today-Rajneesh, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 22)
    - Psych 199, John Jacob, Legal Aspects of Brainwashing, Cults, Rajneesh, 1985 Mar; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 22)
    - Mind Control: 1. Brother Julius, God (30 min.), 2. Swiss Cult Solar Temple... Nightline (30 min.), 1993-1994; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 23)
    - Mind Control: 1. Churches of Christ, 2. Boston-20/20 (4 Programs), 3. 5th Estate, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 23)
    - The Children of Jonestown, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 23)
    - 1. Guyana Tragedy (3 Hrs.) 001-1276, 2. New Report Re: Jonestown, 1981 May 27; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 23)
    - 1. Mind Control-Mary Kay (14 Min.), 2. Rajneesh and Violence, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 23)
    - Guyana Tragedy-Part 1 of 2, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 23)
    - Koresh-NBC Docu-Drama, Ambush in Waco (2 hrs.), 1993 May 23; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 23)
    - 1. Propaganda-World War II: Nazi vs. U.S. (1 Hr.); 2. J. Jones at Ukiah, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 23)
    - MGM-Ticket to Heaven, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 23)
    - Mind Control: The Begging Gone, 1. Strategies, 2. Maximum Insecurity, 1995 Feb; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 23)
    - CAN: 1. Margaret Singer, 2. Robert Jay Lilton, 1989; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 23)
    - 1. Golden 40 Record, 2. Cults (1 hr.), 3. Oliver Twist (2 hrs.), 1981; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 23)
    - Rajneesh Cults (30 min.), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 23)
    - "Killer Cults," Berthillier & Vaillot, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 23)
    - "Cults" Documentary, Interview with Jim Philps-Tape 1, 1 videotape(s) (u-matic) (Box 23)
    - "Cults" Documentary, Interview with Jim Philps-Tape 2, 1 videotape(s) (u-matic) (Box 23)
    - "Cults" Documentary, Interview with Zimbardo-Tape 1, 1 videotape(s) (u-matic) (Box 23)
    - "Cults" Documentary, Interview with Zimbardo-Tape 2, 1 videotape(s) (u-matic) (Box 23)
    - Stanford Football, TV Commercials, 1998; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 24)
    - Stanton Glantz-Mind Control, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 24)
    - Hypnosis Film-Hilgard (27 min.), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 24)
    - Dateline: "Friendly Persuasion" & "Green-eyed Monster", 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 24)
    - Mind Control-Con Games (30 min.), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 24)
    - Oliver, Brenda, & Simone's-Memory of a survivor, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 24)
    - Holocaust Survivor-Valerie Wolfe, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 24)
    - Holocaust Section-Video clip 1-2 versions, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 24)
    - Blood & Honor-Youth Under Hitler 001-651, Parts 1 & 2, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 24)
    - Paranoia-Zimbardo, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 24)
    - The World at War, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 24)
    - Panama Deception-Mind Control, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 24)
    - Bazerman, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 24)
    - Relating to Others-Ann Weber, 1997 May 19; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 24)
    - Conspiracy, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 24)
    - Alcohol/Condom Video: MacDonald, Zanna, & Fong, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 24)
    - 1. Deeper in hypnosis, Hilgard, 2. Obedience, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 24)
    - Valerie Wolfe-Mind Control-Holocaust section-Survivor Stories, 1995 Spring; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 24)
    - Ignacio Martin-Baro, Psychological Effects of Political Terrorism, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 24)
    - Mind Control Overview, ZM Productions, 1997; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 24)
    - Hitler-Rise & Fall of the Third Reich, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 24)
    - Smoking in China-Mind Control, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 24)
    - Tyrants-Part 3-Roots of Evil, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 24)
    - Roots of Evil-Ordinary People-Program 1, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 24)
    - Mind Control-Deviance, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 24)
    - Stand Firm Conf. Talk-21 minutes, Jehovah's Witness- Holocaust Survivors, 2000 Apr 5; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 24)
    - Fears-Media-Risk-Hype, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 24)
    - Japanese Internment California Militia, 1995 May 10; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 24)
    - Rene-Holocaust Survivor, 1995 May; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 24)
    - JFK-In His Words, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 24)
    - Mind Control: Jerry Tolley, Flirtation and Seduction, 1991 Apr 17; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 24)
    - Night of "Control", 1987 Feb 12; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 24)
    - Thornwall-LSD-Brainwashing, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 24)
    - Discovering Psychology: #107, "Sensation & Perception", 1989 Jul; 1 videotape(s) (u-matic) (Box 24)
    - Keys To Paradise, 1982; 1 videotape(s) (u-matic) (Box 24)
    - Unlabeled, 1 videotape(s) (Box 24)
    - Jim Jones-PT-Time Stoen's Story (15 Min.), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 25)
    - Jonestown News, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 25)
    - Jim Jones: A & E (missing opener), 1999 May; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 25)
    - Jonestown; PT; Jim Jones, 1999; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 25)
    - Jim Jones & Peoples Temple, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 25)
    - The Children of Jonestown, Parts I, II, III & Roll of Pix only, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 25)
    - The Children of Jonestown, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 25)
    - TA Workshop, Patricia Ryan (Drama); "Classroom Improvisation Techniques: The TAs Best Friend", 1999 Feb 17; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 25)
    - Psychics on TV, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 25)
    - 1. Divided Memories-Part I, 2. Air Force Academy-POW rape training, 3. Divided Memories, Part 2, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 25)
    - Black River Falls High School AP Psychology Class, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 25)
    - Advertising & Marketing (Stanford Cologne & Join the KBG), 1991; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 25)
    - Birth of Militia, 1997 Sep 3; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 25)
    - 1. 48 Hours: Tough Love, 2. Behavior Mod. Programs, 1998 Oct 15; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 25)
    - 1. Negative Political Ads; 2. School of Assassins; 3. Genocide, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 25)
    - ABC: Turning Point, Charles Manson, Patricia Krenwinkel, Leslie Van Houten, D. Sawyer, 1964 Mar 9; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 25)
    - The Burning Times: Witches in Europe, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 25)
    - Japanese Unit in WWII (partial), Dateline, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 25)
    - Bill Moyers-Public Mind-3/4, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 25)
    - "Five Steps to Tyranny" BBC2, 2000 Dec 19; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 25)
    - The Shop on the Main Street, Oscar Film-Czechoslovakia, 1965; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 25)
    - 20/20-1. Münchausen Disease in a Mother, 2. Pornography & College Students, 1993 Jan 29; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 25)
    - 1. Shyness Quark, 1984, 2. 20/20 Program on Shyness, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 28)
    - Shy Cartoon (Italian), 1 videotape(s) (u-matic) (Box 28)
    - Shyness Composite, 1994; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 28)
    - Psychodrama, Psych. & Drama, 1986 Mar; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 28)
    - Psych/Drama Student Projects (1. psychodrama; 2. shyness stage fright; 3. emotion & time), 1984 May; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 28)
    - Continuing Studies: The Times of Our Lives #3, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 28)
    - Socio-Drama: Talley, Demo in Psych. & Drama, 1985; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 28)
    - Shyness 20/20, 3-year Follow-up, 1987 Sep; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 28)
    - Psych. Research: Video Clips (key points), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 28)
    - Psych. 199; V. Hernandez; Winter '89-'90; Marketing project commercials, 1989-1990; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 28)
    - Course Information-Blackboard, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 28)
    - Shyness in Preschool Children (open reel), 1 videotape(s) (Box 28)
    - Shy Child (black & white), 1 videotape(s) (u-matic) (Box 28)
    - Shyness Dub, 1984 Oct 26; 1 videotape(s) (u-matic) (Box 28)
    - Robert Irvin-Artist, Bill Turner, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 81)
    - 1. Zimbardo, 2. Shyness Interview, 3. Tom Snyder Show, 4. Phil Donahue show, 1 videotape(s) (u-matic) (Box 28)
    - Shyness Film, 1 videotape(s) (u-matic) (Box 28)
    - Dating (black & white), 1 videotape(s) (u-matic) (Box 28)
    - Pain of Shyness, 20/20, 1984 (Box 28)
    - Eye on the Prize-Program 1, Civil Rights, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 31)
    - Bernie Carducci, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 31)
    - Prison: New Mexico State Prison, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 31)
    - Role Playing: The Power of the Situation, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 31)
    - E. Eger, Psychology 1, 1997 May; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 31)
    - Michael Posner Talk, 1988 Apr 21; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 31)
    - Martha Curtis, 60 Minutes (13 min.), 1996 Dec 29; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 31)
    - Martha Curtis, Violinist with Epilepsy, brain surgery, 1995; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 31)
    - Martha Curtis Performance, Psych 1--Zimbardo, 1998 Spring; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 31)
    - Dateline: "Brother's Keeper", 1996 Apr 30; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 31)
    - Dateline: "The Choke Sign", 1997 Aug 3; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 31)
    - Corrections: T. Koppel, 1998 Aug; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 31)
    - Nurenberg to Nurenberg-Rise and Fall of the Third Reich-Part 2, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 31)
    - Hitler-Seduction of a Nation (1 Hr.), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 31)
    - Holocaust-Auschwitz (designers), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 31)
    - Shoah, Nazi-1 of 2, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 31)
    - Shoah, Nazi-2 of 2, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 31)
    - Hitler's Rise to Power, The Race to Build the A Bomb, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 31)
    - Alcatraz Movie, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 31)
    - Pelican Bay Prison, Supermax Isolation, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 31)
    - 3 Strikes Law, 1999 Jun; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 31)
    - Inspection: We Should Not Be Among the Living, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 31)
    - A Clockwork Orange (10 minutes), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - Violence in America, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - Greek Torture & Marine Boot Camp Inserts, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - Pride or Prejudice, 2000 Mar 19; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - Discovery Channel: The Roots of Evil, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - 12 Angry Men: Showtime, 1997, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - The Third Life, Psych SciFi TV Film, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - L.A. Riots-Why it Got Out of Control-Nightline, Ted Koppel, 1992 May 28; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - Police Tapes-Interrupted by PGZ, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - Nightline on Mrs. Eliot Status Expt.-Ramtha 20/20, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - Violence-Bill Moyers, 6 Hours, Part 1: Media & Violence, Part 2: Solutions, 1994 Jan 9-1994 Jan 11; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - Full Metal Jacket-Marine Boot Camp, 2 Hours, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - Violence in America, 1/6/95, 3 hours, 1995 Jan 6; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - Rodney King-Complete Video-Police Beatings, 1992; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - Superquark "Zoo Umano", 2002 Jan 3; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - Mesmer, Alan Rickman, 1994; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - Frat House/Evil Power, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - Torture Mix, 1997 Mar; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - Torture: Mix of Clips: Mind Control, 1997 Mar; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - Torture: Mind Control Training, Brazil, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - Torture, 1995 Sep 5; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - 1. Mrs. Eliott's Class Exp. reunion, 2. Ramtha Cults, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - Lord of the Flies, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - Harold and Maude (Time), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - Paranoia, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - Ground Hog Day, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - 1. Rocky 3; 2. Motivation & Emotion; 3. Psych 1. Final Fight, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - Sybil, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - Miss Evers' Boys: Tuskegee Study, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - 1. Greek Torture & Marine Boot Camp Inserts; 2. CBC War, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - "Children & Violence," Face the Nation Panel, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - The Roots of Evil, Program #1-The Tyrant, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - The Roots of Evil, Program #2, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - The Roots of Evil, Program #3-Tyrants, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - The Roots of Evil, Program #1-Ordinary People, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - The Roots of Evil, Program #2--Ordinary People, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - The Roots of Evil, Program #3-The Torturer, 1998; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 32)
    - Shyness Clinic, 1977 May; 1 videotape(s) (u-matic) (Box 33)
    - 1. Beatles-Time (1964); 2. Harold & Maude; 3. Hippie Era, Anti-Vietnam playfulness; 4. Hair; 5. Beatles-All You Need is Love + Commentary, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 33)
    - Human Zoo, Part I, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 33)
    - Human Zoo, Part II, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 33)
    - Human Zoo, Part III, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 33)
    - Zimbardo on Lester Holt Live, MSNBC, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 33)
    - Milgram Clip, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 33)
    - Milgram-Obedience, 50 min., 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 33)
    - Memory, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 33)
    - Black River Falls High School AP Psychology Classes, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 33)
    - Human Zoo, Part I, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 33)
    - Human Zoo, Programme 1, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 33)
    - Zimbardo, Kindercity, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 33)
    - Shyness, 20/20, 1984 May 15; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 33)
    - The Persuaders, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 33)
    - TPI Dilemmas, 1 of 3, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 34)
    - TPI Dilemmas, 2 of 3, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 34)
    - TPI Dilemmas, 3 of 3, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 34)
    - Exp. 1982 ONR Face-to-Face Groups; Tape F1-Groups: FO1-6, F11-15, 1982 April; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 34)
    - Dr. Z vs. Jackie Chan, Stanford Stadium, 1996 Oct 12; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 34)
    - Tribute to Phil's Retirement, 2003 Nov 1; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 34)
    - Interviews (N=12, S# 92, 42, 43, 96, 84, 68, 72, 71, 62, 87, 93, 74), 1985 Oct 29; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 34)
    - Interviews (N=12, S#63, 70, 77, 67, 81, 88, 65, 79, 85, 91, 75, 18), 1985 Oct 29; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 34)
    - Unexplained Arousal (s# 18, 32, 33, 42, 45, 68, 72, 87, 93, 74), 1985; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 34)
    - Shyness: Zimbardo (32 min); 1. 20/20 ABC-TV Pain & Shyness, 2. Discovering Psychology-Shy Child/shy monkey/shy adult, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 34)
    - No. B-12 [4 sections on participants #68, #79, #67, #91], 1985 May 7-1985 May 8; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 34)
    - 1. Today Show-Shy Child (5 min.), 2. Sex ed., 3. Candid Camera, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 34)
    - Zimbardo-Teaching Workshop; APA; The First Class; Intro. Psychology, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 34)
    - Martha Curtis; Zimbardo-Psych 001, 1997 Apr 16; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 34)
    - Tuskegee Syphilis Study-NOVA "Deadly Deception", 1995; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 34)
    - 1. Nova: Keys to Paradise, 2. J. Campbell: My This Hero's, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 34)
    - NOVA: Great Moments; The Man Who Loved Numbers; The Miracle of Life, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 34)
    - First Feeling-Nova, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 34)
    - NOVA Films: DNA, Apes, & Alcoholism, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 34)
    - The Senses: 5 Parts, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 34)
    - Nova: Keys to Paradise, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 34)
    - NOVA: The Pinks and the Blues, genders, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 34)
    - NOVA: It's About Time, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 34)
    - The Mind: Bipolar Disorder, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 34)
    - The Mind: Thinking, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 34)
    - Love Tapes-Wendy Clark, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 34)
    - Human Zoo, (w/o demonstrations), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 34)
    - Human Zoo, Part 1, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 34)